<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Readings on Jared Connor </title>
    <link>https://jaredtconnor.github.io/reading/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Readings on Jared Connor </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2018 19:04:32 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jaredtconnor.github.io/reading/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Conversations with Tyler: Robin Wiblin from 80000 Hours</title>
      <link>https://jaredtconnor.github.io/reading/conversations-with-tyler-robin-wiblin-from-80000-hours/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2018 19:04:32 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaredtconnor.github.io/reading/conversations-with-tyler-robin-wiblin-from-80000-hours/</guid>
      <description>I feel fairly comfortable stating that this is my favorite podcast of the year. Nearly anything that Tyler Cowen touches is filled to the Brim with nuggets of insight, but this piece takes the cake for being the most comprehensive categorization of his thoughts on moral philosophy, economics, how one should order themselves in the current economy and so on.
It seems fitting that Robin Wiblin would be the person to incite such a conversation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kierkegaard on boredom</title>
      <link>https://jaredtconnor.github.io/reading/kierkegaard-on-busyness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaredtconnor.github.io/reading/kierkegaard-on-busyness/</guid>
      <description>Kierkegaard on Boredom and Busyness: This was a great article about Soren Kierkegaard&amp;rsquo;s discourse on being busy. This article is incredibly easy to resonate with. Opposed to wallowing in the modern competitiveness of keeping up with the Jones, one should realize the drive for one to be busy as an indication of spinning their wheels to no ultimate aim or end.
A short passage from the article:
 For Kierkegaard, busy people are experiencing something indeterminate because their activities are not directed towards some particular good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heads or Tails: The Impact of a Coin Toss on Major Life Decisions and Subsequent Happiness</title>
      <link>https://jaredtconnor.github.io/reading/heads-or-tails-experiment/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 20:59:37 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaredtconnor.github.io/reading/heads-or-tails-experiment/</guid>
      <description>Interesting paper by the ever excellent Steven Levitt, HEADS OR TAILS: THE IMPACT OF A COIN TOSS ON MAJOR LIFE DECISIONS AND SUBSEQUENT HAPPINESS</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interactive Exploration of Dead End Careers</title>
      <link>https://jaredtconnor.github.io/reading/interactive-exploration-of-dead-end-careers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaredtconnor.github.io/reading/interactive-exploration-of-dead-end-careers/</guid>
      <description>I read this wonderful analysis, originally posted by Zippia on the dynamics of salaries across age and labor demographics, via the PUMS (Public Use Microdata Sample) for you acronym junkies out there. While they attempted to view so called dead end jobs, which they roughly define as jobs that lack little wage growth later in their lives, the analysis illustrates a developing trend - the gradual widening of the high skill/high wage labor and low skill/low wage/service oriented labor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Readings_for_6 20 2018</title>
      <link>https://jaredtconnor.github.io/reading/readings-for-6-20-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaredtconnor.github.io/reading/readings-for-6-20-2018/</guid>
      <description>The US Startup is Disappearing and Thats Bad for the Economy This was recently published from Quartz depicting the decline in companies with the age of 0-2 years old, originally published by the BLS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predict Economics Indicators with OpenStreetMap</title>
      <link>https://jaredtconnor.github.io/reading/predict-economic-indicators-with-openstreetmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaredtconnor.github.io/reading/predict-economic-indicators-with-openstreetmap/</guid>
      <description>This was a really cool article regarding the use of OpenStreeMap to predict the economic potential and output of a country. Specifically he is using publicly labeled tags and indicators of schools, universities, lamp posts, and post offices to see how much production and economic activity is coming from a specific region!
This could be of great use for economic research in countries where reliable data is a problem or to view competitive economies from a bird&amp;rsquo;s eye view (no pun intended).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>